

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Chicago, IL USA

🛮 (224) 258-2804 | 🔀 contact@rasheedsaad.com | 💣 www.rasheedsaad.com | 🖸 srashee

Summary.

I'm currently a Software Engineer at Indeed writing customer facing full stack applications. I'm currently working with React, Java and PostgreSQL. I'm passionate about building, tinkering and making things better. I have experience developing on embedded systems, cloud technologies and machine learning platforms.

Work Experience _____

IndeedIndeed.com Company Pages

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

May 2022 - Present

- Migrated legacy Jenkins automation infrastructure to serverless Github Actions suite which resulted in concurrent automated tasks, 5x faster build times and centralized development.
- Mentored, assisted and helped grow junior Indeed engineers and an offshore development team.
- Resolved critical infrastructure issues which resulted in successfully migrating to AWS.
- · Architected and developed many customer facing features for applicant tracking systems

Accenture Industry X

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Apr 2021 - May 2022

- Leader on a team to contribute and build a greenfield healthcare e-commerce solution which led to quick market feedback for a large retailer.
- Built automated tooling and HIPAA compliant full-stack applications using Salesforce solutions which resulted in fault tolerant and automated Salesforce deployments.
- · Scaled out a Smart City data ingestion pipeline while managing and developing multiple micro services in Kubernetes.

Motorola Solutions Secure Products Group

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Jan 2018 - Apr 2021

- · Developed encryption software and security related features for the Motorola's next generation radio, APX NEXT.
- · Developed software across multiple teams across multiple countries and built solutions for cross team development.
- · Architected and developed automation pipeline for embedded devices, enabling automated QA, deployments and testing.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER I

- Worked on a security feature for the Motorola GRV Comparator.
- Developed test code for IoT TCP/UDP devices in C.
- · Helped design and build automated infrastructure and tooling for embedded devices.

Education

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Urbana-Champaign, Illinois

M.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2019 - 2022

Relevant Courses: Distributed Systems (Cloud Computing), Parallel Programming, Theory and Practice of Data Cleaning, Text Information Systems, Foundations of Data Curation, Programming Languages & Compilers, Applied Machine Learning & Deep Learning for Healthcare.

Northern Illinois University

Dekalb, Illinois

B.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2015 - 2017

- · Distinction: Cum Laude
- Relevant Courses: Data Structures, Algorithms, UNIX, Networking, Databases, iOS Mobile Programming, Assembler Mainframe, Java, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture and Systems

Skills

- Languages: Typescript, Javascript, Java, C, C++, Python, Swift, SQL, Haskell, HTML, CSS, Bash
 - **Tools:** Git, Docker, GDB, Spring Boot, React, React Native, Electron, ARM debugger, npm, Clearcase, Jenkins,
- Github Actions, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform, Artifactory, Conan, Jupyter, AWS, CMake, EKS, EC2, PostgresSQL, PrestoDB, NextJS, Vite, Vue, GraphQL, Typescript, Apollo, gRPC and SFRA
- **Embedded:** GPIO, USB, Serial, RS232, and SPI Interfaces
- Security: Experience working with encryption algorithms, CIS20 Controls and OWASP Top 10
- ◀ Hobbies: Building & Flying FPV Drones, Photography, 3D Printing & Chess

Projects

Clear Head clrhead.com

FULL STACK APPLICATION Jan. 2022 - Present

- Building a full stack application that centralizes your day to day allowing you to have a clear head.
- Built with NextJS, Typescript, Express, Apollo, GraphQL, Prisma and PostgreSQL

Motorola YPG SCH Motorola Solutions

SOCIAL BRANCH LEAD Jan. 2020 - Apr 2021

- · Led a team to setup events for Motorola social events.
- Event planning for virtual events during the pandemic.
- Event planning for social in-person events for 500 attendants.

Causal Data Mining CS410: Text Information Systems

ITERATIVE TOPIC MODELING WITH TIME SERIES FEEDBACK

October 2020

- · Worked with a team to develop a system in Python to analyze historical data and build graphical associations with historical events.
- The project and code is an open-sourced research project available for viewing.

Google Extension Google Chrome Store

MINIMALIST Feb. 2019 - Present

• Developed and maintain a minimal note taking application for Google Chrome.

· Available for download in the Google Chrome Store.

ACM WCS Mentorship Program

University of Illinois at UC

MENTOR May. 2020

- · Mentored an Ungraduate Computer Science student.
- Met virtually on a regular cadence to help matriculation during the COVID 19 Pandemic.

Motorola Hackathon Schaumburg, Illinois

TECHNICAL ENABLEMENT LEAD Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019

- Led a team to setup required technical infrastructure for hackathon, hosting approximately 100 participants.
- · Team enabled participants to use GitLab, GitHub, Cloud Instances alongside proprietary Motorola hardware.

iOS Application Northern Illinois University

UniBoard Dec. 2016 - Feb. 2018

- Developed a social media iOS application in Swift 3 that allowed university students to sign up and communicate publicly through posts and
- Used Firebase for the back-end and data store to allow users to comment and like other user's posts.